Let us now talk about Bootstraps own support for navigation.
接下来让我们学习 Bootstrap 自身对导航的一些支持
In particular, in this lecture, we will talk about the Bootstrap's Navbar.
特别地 我们要学习 Bootstrap 的导航栏
Navbar is a very easy
使用导航栏是一种很易懂地
way of providing navigational information within your website.
为一个网站提供导航的方式
Let's look at the details next.
接下来让我们看看其实现的细节
As I already mentioned,
我刚刚说了
the Navbar is a way of easily providing navigation for your website.
导航栏是一种易懂的提供导航的方式
The Navbar typically appears at the top of the page or
它常常出现在一个页面 的抬头处或是底部
the bottom of the page depending upon the design of your website.
这取决于你对网站的设计样式
Now, Navbars can also support responsive features,
导航栏还支持响应式设计
meaning that when you're viewing the website on a extra small screen.
这意味着当你的网站在一个 很小的屏幕上被访问时
Maybe you may wish to collapse the Navbar and
你可以把你的导航栏折叠起来
only display content by toggling the information appropriately.
并在相应的位置留下合适的信息
For larger screen sizes,
对于比较大的屏幕
it is probably more easier to accommodate a full fledged navigation bar.
自然就能把完整的导航栏呈现出来
So we will look at bootstrap support for both situations in more detail next.
对于这两种情况 我们接下来会学到 Bootstrap 对它们的相关支持
Let's talk in particular, about a simple navigation bar that can be provided
首先先让我们实现一个简单的导航栏
within bootstrap and how we go about configuring it.
并由此看看 Bootstrap 的导航栏 大概长什么样吧
So here I have an example of a simple navigation bar and
那么这里就是一个导航栏的栗子
the corresponding code that is used in Bootstrap to design this navigation bar.
效果在上面 代码在下面
Now I am leveraging the Nav HTML element to design my navigation bar.
我用到了 HTML 中的 nav 标签 来实现导航栏
To this nav HTML element, I am using
对这个 nav 标签 我设置了一系列属性
the Navbar classes that are available as part of Bootstrap.
其中设置的类是 Bootstrap 相关的类
The Navbar, which turns that HTML element into a Navbar and the Navbar default.
其中 class="navbar" 会将该 nav 标签 变成一个导航栏
So this is the default structuring of the navigation bar in Bootstrap or
而 navbar-default 则是对其样式的定制 顾名思义 也就是 Bootstrap
the default coloring and so on.
默认的导航栏样式 比如说应用默认的颜色之类的
Also notice that I am declaring that this Navbar takes
除了设置类以外 我还设置了 role="navigation"
on the role of providing navigation within this website.
意味着该 nav 标签将会 为该网站提供导航
Now let's look at the example Navbar on the screen and
框架搭好之后 让我们来看看
then see how this is actually constructed by using the HTML code below there.
怎么设置这个导航栏中的内容吧
In particular, you see that the list of items being displayed in
特别的 你可以看到 导航栏中的每一项内容
the Navbar is declared in the code as an unsorted list
都是作为 ul 标签下的一个 li 元素存在的
with the class nav navbar-nav.
其中要对 ul 标签设置 class="nav navbar-nav"
And within these each list item is displayed using li and
至于其下的 li 标签 只需将导航栏中的每一项作为其内容即可
then you provide the href through the normal HTML links there.
当然 由于每一项都是个链接 所以要用 a 标签包起来 同时还要设置 href
One particular list item has been identified as the active list item there.
然后对其中之一还要设置 class="active" 意味着这是最初被选择的一项
So for this example, I have identified the Home as the active list item.
在这个栗子里 我对 Home 对应的 li 设置了 class="active"
What this means is that in the Bootstrap's Navbar, this Home item is highlighted
所以在一开始 你可以看到
with a darker color for the default Navbar as you can see on the screen.
Home 这一项被高亮了
I am now extending the Navbar into Into adding more features.
接下来我要拓展这个导航栏 以加进更多的功能
One, is that I am adding in what we call as a brand to the navbar.
其一是我加进了一个商标
So within the Navbar on the left side,
你可以看到在导航栏左侧
you can see the name of the website being displayed there.
有一个我们网站的商标
That name will form part of the Navbar header.
实现的方式是用一个设置了 class="navbar-header" 的 div
And inside the navbar header, which is a separate div there,
然后在其中我用了一个设置了 class="navbar-brand" 的 a 标签
I am declaring a class called navbar-brand to a link and
意味着这一块将会是一个商标
then I am providing that link there.
我还设置了其 href 属性 也就是其将指向的地址
Now you can replace the text within that link by
你可以将这些文字替换成一张图像
an actual image which might be the logo of your website.
比如说 logo 什么的
So that's another way of providing navigation within the navbar,
那么这其实蕴含了一个 实现导航栏时常用的手段
specifically using the logo navigation.
也就是在导航栏里塞一个 logo 作为返回主页的导航
Typically, when you put the logo into the navbar, users expect that when they click
因为如果你在导航栏里放一个 logo 的话
on that logo, they are going to be taken back to the home page of the navbar.
"点击 logo 将会返回主页" 这个事实 已经几乎是约定俗成的了
So when you specify the href for
所以当你设置这个 logo 的 href 属性时
that class there, you should make sure that it is identifying your home page.
你要注意把它设置成主页的地址
We can also similarly put items to the right side,
类似的 我们还可以将东西
right into the screen within the navbar.
放在导航栏的右侧
To do that, we are going to use the nav navbar-nav for
为此 除了对 ul 标签的 class 属性
the unsorted list that we've seen already.
设置 nav 和 navbar-nav 之外
In addition, we're going to supply another attribute called navbar-right.
还要多设置一个
When you specify that,
navbar-right
there are list items that are gonna be put on the right edge of the navbar.
这样一来 在这个 ul 下面的元素 就会放置在导航栏的右边
For left edge you, would say navbar-left, for right edge you would say navbar-right.
同理对左边就是 navbar-left
We can make the navbar also responsive.
我们还能把导航栏做成响应式的
Meaning that when you are viewing the website on an extra small screen or
意味着当你在比较小的屏幕上 浏览你的网站
any chosen size of the screen.
或是任何其它大小的屏幕上浏览时
You can collapse the navbar and hide the items within the navbar.
你都可以让你的导航栏折叠起来
And instead replace it with a toggle button as you see in the picture here.
并在相应的地方放一个开关按钮
When the user clicks on the toggle button, then you will expand the navigation
你可以做到只有当用户 点击这个开关按钮时
bar to show the link items, like so.
才把你的导航栏展开
When the user again clicks on the toggle button,
然后当用户再次点击时
you're going to hide those navigation items.
又把导航栏折叠起来
So this behavior can easily be supported within Bootstrap
如果应用 Bootstrap 的话
using the toggle button that can be included in the header,
你可以轻松地将这么一个开关按钮
nav-navbar header of your Bootstrap.
放在你的导航栏中
We will see how that is done in the next slide.
对于其具体代码实现 我们会在下节课中学习
Now we are going to examine how to design this responsive navbar.
接下来让我们会大概看一下其实现
First, we need a toggle button within the navbar.
首先一个开关按钮
So this is usually included in the navbar-header as shown by the code here.
一般是放在 navbar-header 里面的
So in here, I am declaring a button type.
然后它本身则是一个 button 标签 同时对其要设置
And the class I am using is navbar-toggle and also specified as collapsed.
class="navbar-toggle collapsed" 其中设置的 collapsed 属性代表的是
Meaning that the items that this Button is referring to will be in the collapsed mode
接下来的设置是该按钮在 导航栏被折叠时所表现出来的
when you are viewing this page on an extra small device.
比如说在一个很小的屏幕上 浏览该网页时 该按钮的表现
When the user clicks on this button, then the further
而当用户点击这个按钮时 该导航栏就会展开
details are the extended navbar will be toggled and shown on the screen.
你可以看到我在 button 里面放了三个设置了 class="icon-bar" 的 span, 所以在这个按钮中
Now this is implemented by enclosing the items
你可以看到三条横杠 注意 对导航栏展开后的内容
within the list inside a div and giving it an id.
要以 ul 标签的形式封装在一个 div 中 同时对这个 div 要设置一个 id
This id in this example, the id given is navbar and
在这个栗子里 我把 id 设置为了 navbar
that id is used as a data target for the button.
所以对那个开关按钮 就要设置 data-target="#navbar"
What exactly is a data target and how is it used?
看到这里你可能会想问 这里这个 data-target 的具体实现原理是什么
For that, we need to understand that JavaScript
这个问题的答案要涉及到
modules that were implemented in Bootstrap.
对 Bootstrap 中 JavaScript 模块的理解
So I'm going to come back to refer to this one more time in the module
所以在我们讨论 Bootstrap 中的 JavaScript 的时候
where we look at JavaScript within Bootstrap.
我会回过头来再看这一部分
But here, let's understand that
不过现在的话 只需要知道
this id is also used to specify the data target for the button.
这个 data-target 和这个 id 之间要一致 就已经够了
Meaning that that button is going to toggle on and
这意味着我将下面这个 div 中的内容
off, whatever is inside this div on the screen.
"绑定"在了这个开关按钮上
Now for this div in addition,
同时对下面这个 div 我要对其设置
I'm going to give the class as navbar collapse and collapse.
class="navbar-collapse collapse"
Meaning that initially when you are viewing this
意味着如果你一开始在 很小的屏幕上浏览该页面的话
page on an extra small screen, the navbar will start out collapsed.
那么这个 div 中的内容就会被折叠
When the user clicks on the button, then the navbar will be toggled and vice versa.
只有在用户点击了这个开关按钮后 这个 div 中的内容才会被呈现
Some additional configurations that you can give for navbars,
对于导航栏 你还可以定制更多东西
include specifying that the navbar should be fixed to the top of the page.
比如说你可以令其 固定在当前页面的上方
Meaning that the navbar is always visible and will be fixed at the top of the page.
意味着该导航栏将总是 在你视野上方出现
The content will scroll, but the navbar will remain fixed in that location.
随着你滚动页面 页面的主体内容可能会跟着滚动 但导航栏却总是在上方的一个固定位置出现
You can also similarly fix the navbar at the bottom.
当然你也能把导航栏钉在底部
The corresponding classes are indicated here.
只要设置相应的类即可 上 下方的类分别是
.Navbar-fixed-top and .navbar-fixed-bottom.
navbar-fixed-top 和 navbar-fixed-bottom
There are other specification that you can give is to specify the navbar
你同样能让导航栏 固定在页面的某一个地方
as navbar-static-top.
设置时 将 fixed 改成 static 就行
Meaning that this navbar will be at the top of the page, but
这意味着导航栏会出现在 页面的上方或下方
will scroll when you scroll the page.
而且会随着页面的滚动而滚动
So the navbar will disappear from the screen when you scroll the page up.
也就是当你往下滚动页面到一定程度 你就看不到你的导航栏了
In Bootstrap, earlier we saw that we declared the navbar as navbar default.
之前我们实现导航栏时 用的是 navbar-default
The default navbar for bootstrap is a light colored navigation bar.
也就是 Bootstrap 默认的导航栏样式 给人的总体印象浅色的
You can also have a dark colored navigation bar in bootstrap by providing
你也可以设置为深色的
the class as navbar-inverse instead of navbar-default.
只要用 navbar-inverse 替换就行
So in the navbar-inverse, the background of the navbar will be dark in color but
此时 导航栏的背景将会是深色的
the text will be lighter in color.
而文字则会是浅色的
One last addition to the navbar that is often used,
最后要介绍的一个导航栏的功能
is what we refer to as a dropdown.
就是下拉菜单了
When we talk about a dropdown,
事实上 导航栏中的任一项
any item within the navbar can be turned into a dropdown.
都能变成一个下拉菜单
So that when the user clicks on the item, then you would display
当用户点击一个下拉菜单时
a list of dropdown
它会显示一系列东西
items to the user and then allow them to select one of those dropdown items.
然后用户可以接着点击 其感兴趣的链接
Similarly, when you click on the item in the navbar,
如果你再次点击那下拉菜单的话
then we will hide this dropdown, right?
这些东西就会被收起来
So this toggling of this dropdown list of items is done
总之 下拉菜单中的内容显示与否
by clicking on the item inside the navbar.
正是由导航栏中 对应的下拉菜单控制的
In this example, if you click on the Menu item in the navbar,
在这个栗子里 如果你点击 导航栏中 Menu 这一项
it will display the detailed list there.
它就会将一系列东西呈现出来
If you click on it again, then that detail list will disappear.
如果你再次点击这个 Menu 按钮 这些东西就会被收起来
So this is the use of dropdowns in navbar.
这就是下拉菜单的效果
How do we implement it?
这是怎么实现的呢？
We'll examine that next.
如何实现一个下拉菜单
So to implement the dropdown, we need to Declared the drop down
为此 我们需要用一个设置了 class="dropdown" 的 li 标签
as a list item within the unsorted list that we used
注意这个 li 标签正是之前设置了 class="nav navbar-nav" 的
to construct the navbar links there.
ul 标签下的众多 li 标签中的一个
Now one of the items will be declared as a list item of the type dropdown.
只不过其设置了 class="dropdown" 以表示其是一个下拉菜单 dropdown 而已
The code on the left side indicates
左边这坨代码是
how you would declare the list item as a dropdown.
对 Menu 这个下拉菜单按钮的定制
And in addition, you specify the class
你可以看到我对其 a 标签
as dropdown-toggle and
设置了 class="dropdown-toggle"
the data would be specified at dropdown, data-toggle as dropdown.
以及 data-toggle="dropdown"
And some additional rows there and
我还设置了其它一些东西
in particular, notice that declaration of the span class caret.
比如在其中放了一个设置了 class="caret" 的 span
Now this is used to show these inverted triangle
这个 span 正是在 Menu 四个字母右边
next to the item within the bar.
那个小小的向下指的三角形
To indicate that when the user clicks on that item,
这个小三角形起到了提示用户
we're ging to show a dropdown list there.
"这是一个下拉菜单" 的作用
Now how do we declare the items within the dropdown list?
那么怎么定制下拉菜单中的内容呢 ?
That will be included as another unsorted list inside this list item.
我们需要用到另一个 ul 标签
And this unsorted list shown on the right side has the class dropdown menu.
我把其代码贴在了右边这里
And individual list items listed there will be shown in
可以看到 下拉菜单中的每一项
the list of items in the dropdown menu.
都被放在了一个单独的 li 标签中
So you can see that these list items correspond with Appetizers,
比如 Appetizers
Main Courses and so on.
Main Courses 之类的
You can also include a separator by declaring the role as a separator and
你也可以加进一条长长的横杠 只需要对相应的一项设置
the class as a divider for one of the list items.
role="separator" 和 class="divider" 即可
You can also have a header there
你还可以在这条横杠下 加一个副标题一样的东西
by declaring a list item with a class dropdown-header.
只需对相应一项设置 class="dropdown-header" 即可
So that that will not be treated as a link, instead it will be treated as
如此 则该项不会被当做一个链接
just a header for the items displayed below.
而是会被当成一个副标题
So this is yet another feature that we will use within the navbar.
总之 下拉菜单是导航栏支持的 相当有用的一个功能
This completes our discussion on Bootstrap Navbar.
以上 我们完成了对 Bootstrap 导航栏的学习
In the exercise that follows, we are going to design a navbar for our webpage.
在接下来的练习中 我们会在我们的网页中 亲自设计并实现一个导航栏
At the end of the exercise, you will see our webpage having a fixed top
然后在完成练习后 我们的网页上方 就会有一个固定的导航栏
navbar as shown in the website details here.
该导航栏将会显示我们网页的一些细节
And this navbar is colored appropriately for our website.
同时我们会把导航栏的颜色 定制得符合我们网站的总体色调
We'll see how we can do that using the CSS class and
这个定制是通过 CSS 类来实现的 同时 我们还会在导航栏中
we also see a dropdown item within the navbar.
实现这么一个下拉菜单 【翻译 - Carefree0910】